Finding Aid for Daniel E. Atkins papers, 1959-2011
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- U-M School of Information 1991-2006
  - Meetings and activities 1991-2002 (in chronological order)
    - Kalamazoo College / Lisa Palchick 1996 (Box 6)
    - Netscape update 1996 (Box 6)
    - National Archives / SI Celebration 1996 (Box 6)
    - Nicholas Beeson 1996 (Box 6)
    - Kellogg Meeting / Derrick Cogburn 1996 (Box 6)
    - SI Student Showcase 1996 (Box 6)
    - UARC Workshop @ Media Union 1996 (Box 6)
    - Dr. Hanns Seidler, Chancellor, Technical University of Darmstadt 1996 (Box 6)
    - Microsoft visit 1996 (Box 6)
    - Deans' brainstorming luncheon 1996 (Box 6)
    - Information Sciences Workshop, UC Santa Barbara 1996 (Box 6)
    - Meeting with John Seeley Brown 1996 (Box 6)
    - Activities chron 1997, 3 folders (Box 6)
    - ALISE 1997 (Box 6)
    - Dagstuhl Workshop, Germany "The University of Michigan Digital Library Projects July 1997" 1997 (Box 6)
    - Media Union director search 1997 (Box 6)
    - Ken Burns honorary degree 1997 (Box 6)
    - Dr. Pramod Magla, Delhi University 1998 (Box 6)
    - NSF Request for Russian Digital Library visit 1998 (Box 6)
    - Dr. Luther Williams, Kellogg meeting 1998 (Box 6)
    - Suzanne Thorin, Indiana University 1998 (Box 6)
    - Lotus briefing 1998 (Box 6)
    - Y.T. Chien Digital Library Initiative information project 1998 (Box 6)
    - Paul Horn visit 1998 (Box 6)
    - Long-range planning meeting with provost 1998 (Box 6)
    - Marshall symposium 1998 (Box 6)
    - Barbara O'Keefe, NCSA 1998 (Box 6)
    - Faculty retreat 1998 (Box 6)
    - Andrew Lippman, MIT 1998 (Box 6)
    - Rick Snyder / Tom Baird KW luncheon 1998 (Box 6)
    - Ameritech meeting 1998 (Box 6)
    - Foundations 1998 (Box 6)
    - Barbara O'Keefe lunch 1998 (Box 6)
    - Nathaniel Borenstein 1998 (Box 6)
    - Committee on Accreditation (COA) 1998 (Box 6)
    - Snowbird Institute Nomination 1998 (Box 6)
    - Stu Feldman /Anat Jhingram 1998 (Box 6)
    - Activities Chron (April -- November 1998 (Box 6)
    - Y.T. Chien visit 1998 (Box 6)
    - Mott meeting 1998 (Box 6)
    - Chuck Henry -- Rice University 1998 (Box 6)
    - Laura Good -- Intel (canceled) 1998 (Box 6)
    - Digital Library Conference, Pittsburgh 1998 (Box 6)
    - Second InterOperability Conference 1998 (Box 6)
    - Mark Miller 1998 (Box 6)
    - Mark Maybury MITRE 1998 (Box 6)
    - Brussels DELOS 1998 (Box 6)
    - Warburg Pincus 1998 (Box 6)
    - Donor lunch 1998 (Box 6)
    - SPARC Meeting 1998 (Box 6)
    - SI Alumni Board Dinner Meeting 1998 (Box 6)
    - Architecture of Knowledge Conference 1998 (Box 6)
    - National Academy of Engineering 1998 (Box 6)
    - National Indian Teleconference (postponed) 1998 (Box 6)
    - Eastman Kodak Crew CTS 1998 (Box 6)
    - Hewlett-Packard Visit 1998 (Box 6)
    - IBM Strategic Alliance (postponed) 1998 (Box 6)
    - School of Dentistry 1998 (Box 6)
    - Microsoft visit 1998 (Box 6)
    - Moscow Russia digital library meeting 1998 (Box 6)
    - Dow 1998 (Box 6)
    - Can we preserve the Internet as we know it? (Mark Cooper, Larry Lessig) 1999 (Box 7)
    - MIT Libraries Visiting Committee 2000 (Box 7)
    - Making Advanced Technology Work for Community Serving Organizations: The Potential Impact of Open Source Software and Application Service Provision, Ann Arbor 2000 (Box 7)
    - Internet Policy Institute (IPI) Workshop 2000 (Box 7)
    - European Conference on Digital Libraries (ECDL), Lisbon 2000 (Box 7)
    - Symposium on Improving Learning with Technology: National Research Council (NRC) 2001 (Box 7)
    - Law, Policy and the Convergence of Telecommunications and Computing Technologies 2001 (Box 7)
    - SI Faculty Retreat 2001 (Box 7)
    - "Silicon Dreams Revisited: Information, People and Machines" 2001 (Box 7)
    - Capacity Builders: Building Global Partnerships, San Francisco 2001 (Box 7)
    - Science of Collaboratories Workshop: The Social Underpinnings of Collaboration 2001 (Box 7)
    - Collaboration in Academe: Establishing Open Course Communities, Ann Arbor 2001 (Box 7)
    - Technical Underpinnings of Collaboratories, Ann Arbor 2001 (Box 7)
    - Digital Collectives in Indigenous Cultures and Communities, Ann Arbor 2001 (Box 7)
    - Internet II 2001 (Box 7)
    - National Academies Committee on Science, Engineering and Public Policy (COSEPUP) 2001 (Box 7)
    - Internet II "Conversation with the president and provost: UM and IT based opportunities and challenges" 2002 (Box 7)
    - NSF Knowledge and distributed intelligence initiative 2002 (Box 7)
    - NSF Workshop on cyberinfrastructure at research institutions 2002 (Box 7)
    - Comparative Investigation of Collaboratories, Ann Arbor 2002 (Box 7)
  - Topical 1992-2006
    - Alliance for Equity in Higher Education 2001 (Box 7)
    - American Council of Learned Societies (ACLS) Commission on Cyber-Infrastructure for the Humanities and Social Sciences 2004-2006, 2 folders (Box 7)
    - American Library Association (ALA) Accreditation 1993-1998 (Box 7)
    - American Society for Information Science (ASIS) 1995-1998 (Box 7)
    - Association of American Universities (AAU) Research Libraries Task Force on a National Strategy for Managing Scientific and Technical Information 1993-1994, 4 folders (Box 7)
      (1-4 of 8 folders)
    - AAU Research Libraries Task Force 1992-1993, 4 folders (Box 8)
      (5-8 of 8 folders)
    - Application Service Providers (ASPs) 1999-2000 (Box 8)
    - Association of American University Presses 1994 (Box 8)
    - Atkins 1994 accomplishments, 1994 (Box 8)
    - Atkins 1995 accomplishments, 1995 (Box 8)
    - Atkins 1996-8 accomplishments, 1996-8 (Box 8)
    - Atkins appointment calendar 1992-1998 (Box 8)
    - Atkins CV 2000 (Box 8)
    - Atkins file index 1991-1992 (Box 8)
    - Atkins mail log 1993-1994 (Box 8)
    - Benton Foundation -- non-profits 2000-2001 (Box 8)
    - Billy, Carrie 2002 (Box 8)
    - Center for International Earth Science Information Network (CIESIN) 1993 (Box 8)
    - Center for Organizations, Information and Technology with Mike Cohen 1993 (Box 8)
    - Collaboratory for Research on Electronic Work (CREW) 1994-1995, 2 folders (Box 8)
    - Collaboratory on Technology -- Enhanced Learning Communities 2000 (Box 8)
    - College of Engineering Faculty Communications 1993-1997, 3 folders (Box 8)
    - Commission on Preservation and Access -- Patricia Battin 1993-1994, 2 folders (Box 8)
    - Committee on Institutional Cooperation (CIC) Summit on Scholarly Communications 2003-2004, 2 folders (Box 8)
    - Consultancies 1995-1997 (Box 8)
    - Consultancies -- Connections -- Rice University 2002 (Box 8)
    - Cyberstate.org 1998-2001 (Box 8)
    - Digital Information Environment Task Force 1993 (Box 8)
    - Digital libraries 2003-2004 (Box 8)
    - Digital Opportunity Trust: A plan for .us (n.d.) (Box 8)
    - Digital Partners Board 2002 (Box 8)
    - Digital Steppingstones Project Final Report 2002 (Box 8)
    - Doctoral Student Handbook 2000-2002 (Box 8)
    - Duderstadt: Challenges of a Knowledge Society 1990 (Box 8)
    - European Activities 1996 (Box 8)
    - Faculty handbook 2002-2003 (Box 8)
    - Faculty visioning exercise 1993 (Box 8)
    - Globalization and the Information Society (Cogburn) 2000 (Box 8)
    - Higher Ed Faces the Digital Age (book contract) 2001 (Box 8)
    - Holland, Maurita "Digital Collectives in Indigenous Cultures and Communities 2001 (Box 8)
    - "Ideas for a New Center or.. ." 1993 (Box 8)
    - Information and Communication Technology (ICT) Steering Committee 2000-2002 (Box 8)
    - Internet II 2000-2002 (Box 9)
    - Librarians for the Future 2002 (Box 9)
    - Lougee, Wendy "Diffuse Libraries: Emergent Roles for the Research Library in the Digital Age" 2002 (Box 9)
    - Media Union Executive Committee 2001 (Box 9)
    - Millennium Project 2001 (Box 9)
    - National Academies: IT and the Future of Research Universities (ITFRU) 1998-2002, 4 folders (Box 9)
    - National Academies: Steering Committee on Electronic, Scientific, Technical and Medical Journal Publishing 2002 (Box 9)
    - National Information Center for Hispanic Education (NICHE) Hispanic Association of Colleges and Universities (HACU) 2001 (Box 9)
    - National Library of Medicine 1999 (Box 9)
    - National Science Foundation (NSF) Blue Ribbon Advisory Panel on Cyberinfrastructure 2001-2003 (Box 9)
    - "New Edition" Dean's message 1993 (Box 9)
    - NPower Board 2001 (Box 9)
    - Organization for Open Source Software (OOSS) 2005-2006, 3 folders (Box 9)
    - Packard Foundation: Capability Builders 2001 (Box 9)
    - Panko, Walter, 1993-1994 (Box 9)
    - Scholarly Communications 2003-2005 (Box 9)
    - School of Information (SI) Doctoral program 2000-2001 (Box 9)
    - SI information, 1995-98 (Box 9)
    - School of Information and Library Science (SILS) Information 1991 (Box 9)
    - Social correspondence 1992-1998 (Box 9)
    - Technology-related Philanthropy and volunteerism grants -- Andrew Blau 2002 (Box 9)
    - Transparencies re: SI and Digital Libraries 1993-1994 (Box 10)
    - Talks undated (Box 10)
    - Unidentified group photograph 1980s (Box 10)
    - University Fort Hare, South Africa 1998-2001 (Box 10)
      (contains photographs)
    - University of Michigan President's Information Revolution Commission Report 2001 (Box 10)
    - University of Michigan strategic priorities 1994 (Box 10)
    - XI Group (Thinking Group) 1994-1995 (Box 10)
  - Digital Library Program 1994-2000
    - Digital Library Program 1994-2000, 10 files (Box 10)
  - Kellogg Foundation 1995-2001
    - Alliance for Community Technology (ACT) Annual Report 2001 (Box 10)
    - ACT miscellaneous 2000-2001 (Box 10)
    - Battle Creek Nonprofit Technology Fair 2001 (Box 10)
    - Clements Library Proposal 1997 (Box 10)
    - CRISTAL-ED project: Interim report #1 with appendices 1995, 3 folders (Box 10)
    - CRISTAL-ED Project -- Interim report #2 with appendices 1996, 3 folders (Box 11)
    - CRISTAL-ED Project -- Interim report #3 and final report 1997-1999 (Box 11)
    - CRISTAL-ED Project -- Site visit 1995 (Box 11)
    - CRISTAL-ED Project -- Transcript WK Kellogg Foundation Meeting: Santa Fe Institute 1996 (Box 11)
    - Educating Human Resources for the Information and Library Professions of the 21st Century, 1993-99 (Box 11)
    - Kellogg Alliance for Community Technology (ACT) 1996-1997 (Box 11)
    - Kellogg II Annual Reports 1997-2000 (Box 11)
    - Kellogg II proposal and award 1996-1997 (Box 11)
    - McClure, Gail D. 1992-1996 (Box 11)
    - Miscellaneous 1994-1999 (Box 11)
    - Proposals 1993-1998 (Box 11)
    - Santa Fe Workshop 1996 (Box 11)
    - State initiatives -- Duderstadt Faculty Panel on Universities in a Digital Age 1997 (Box 11)
    - State initiatives -- State of Michigan Millennium Project 1997 (Box 11)
  - Other funders 1992-2001
    - Ameritech Learning Initiative 1999 (Box 11)
    - Industrial Partners of Computer Science and Engineering (IPoSCE) Review 1993-1994 (Box 11)
    - NSF/ARPA/NASA U-M Digital Library Project Proposal 1994, 2 folders (Box 11)
    - NSF Center for Collaboratories in Science and Engineering preproposal 2001 (Box 11)
    - NSF Center for the Educational Application of Advanced Computer and Communications Technologies (Box 11)
    - NSF Collaboratories as a step toward the future research university preproposal 2000 (Box 11)
    - NSF Digital Libraries Initiative, Phase 2 1998 (Box 11)
    - NSF "DLI-2: A Testbed for Digital Library Applications in Organizations of Civil Society" 2001 (Box 11)
    - NSF Space Physics and Aeronomy Research Collaboratory 1998 (Box 11)
    - NSF "Sustainable and Generalizable Technology to Support Collaboration in Science" 2000 (Box 11)
    - NSF "A Science and Technology Center for Collaboratories in Science and Engineering" proposal 2001 (Box 11)
    - NSF "Testbed-driven Research on Cultural Heritage Federation" 1998 (Box 11)
  - Alliance for Community Technology (ACT) 1991-1998
    - Alliance for Community Technology (ACT) Advisory Group 1998 (Box 12)
    - ACT Circuit Riders 1998 (Box 12)
    - ACT Evaluation 1998 (Box 12)
    - ACT Miller, Mark 1998 (Box 12)
    - ACT Mission slides (n.d.) (Box 12)
    - ACT Social Capital Proposal 1998 (Box 12)
    - Education/Technology Group Meeting 1998 (Box 12)
    - ERCRIM Proposal to NSF 1996 (Box 12)
    - European Digital Library Conf. in Crete 1998 (Box 12)
    - Grantmakers for Education DC Meeting 1998 (Box 12)
    - University Library / Information Technology Senior Managers Retreats 1991-1992 (Box 12)
  - Community Information Corps 2001-2005
    - Alumni network 2004 (Box 12)
    - Annual gathering 2004 (Box 12)
    - Arts of Citizenship 2000-2004 (Box 12)
      Contains CD with Powerpoint
    - City Connect Detroit 2004 (Box 12)
    - CIC Documents from JMK 5/04 2001-2004 (Box 12)
      (CD 20 files: 3 are XLS, 17 are DOC 1.7 MB "CIC-ACT folder for Peter")
    - Conferences 2003 (Box 12)
    - Culture Bus 2005 (Box 12)
    - Digital Partners, 2003-5 (Box 12)
      (Contains CD with 5-minute video)
    - Fellows Professional Development Report 2001-2005 (Box 12)
    - Projects and internships, undated200 (Box 12)
    - Kellogg 1996 grant "Building a Sustainable Model of Practical Learning and Service in Community Organizations", 1996 (Box 12)
    - Kellogg CIC proposal "CIC: Empowering Practical Engagement Experiences" 2004-2005 (Box 12)
    - Meetings 2004-2005 (Box 12)
    - Michigan Community Scholars Program 2004 (Box 12)
    - Operations manual 2003 (Box 12)
    - Partners 2004 (Box 12)
    - Photo directories 2001-2004 (Box 12)
    - Program description 2001-2004 (Box 12)
    - Program manager 2005 (Box 12)
    - Publicity 2003-2004 (Box 12)
      (contains 2 CD's)
    - Publicity logos 2004 (Box 12)
    - Strategic assessment 2003 (Box 12)
    - Projects -- student initiated 2001 (Box 12)
    - Walking project: Arts at Michigan 2005 (Box 12)
    - Web administration 2005 (Box 12)
    - Web design 2003-2004 (Box 12)
- IT Council 2010-2011
  The digital series, IT Council, 2010-2011 (192.5 MB) documents the activities of the IT Council from early 2010 to mid-2011. Materials are arranged in four subseries. The first subseries, IT Council Agendas and Summaries, 2010-2011, consists of agendas and meeting summaries that were publicly presented on the IT Council website. The second subseries, IT Council Meeting Materials, 2010-2011 are files related to materials circulated to Council members at meetings. This subseries contains five folders that group files according to meeting date. The subseries, Pictures, 2010, includes three pictures of the IT Council at work. Finally, the subseries, Strategic Plan Template from Cindy, 2010, includes three files that document the template that Cindy Wells, then Assistant CIO, presented to help Domain Stewards summarize the threats and opportunities in their jurisdictions. Files within this series are mainly word processing documents, PDF files and a small number of image files.
  - IT Council Agendas and Summaries 2010-2011
  - IT Council Meeting Materials 2010-2011
    - 2011_3_11_Materials
    - 2011_4_1_Materials
    - 2011_4_22_Materials
    - 2011_6_3_Materials
    - 2010_11_to_2011_02_Materials
  - Pictures 2010
  - Strategic Plan Template from Cindy 2010
Related Material
The series Project Files of Dan Atkins, 1981-1989 (ca. 3 lin. ft.) in the College of Engineering Record Group documents his tenure as associate dean for research. This series contains six subseries: Department of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science, Experimental Research in Electronic Submission Project (EXPRES), Industrial Technology Institute (ITI), Center for Robotics and Integrated Manufacturing (CRIM), Institute of Science and Technology and Provost Search Advisory Committee. In addition, his tenure as interim dean of the College of Engineering (1989-1990) is documented in the Charles M. Vest subseries of the Dean's Files in the College of Engineering Record Group, generally intermixed with Vest's files. The Gary M. Olson papers, also held by the Bentley contain material related to his collaboration with Atkins on the EXPRES project.